A Guide to the Huddle Family Papers, 1854-1970
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Huddle Family Papers, 1854-1970
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Huddle, Charles, Sr.; Huddle, Charles, Jr.; Huddle, Royall; Huddle family
Ms1989-084
13.2 Cubic Feet 10 boxes; 1 folio
This collection primarily contains papers associated with Charles Huddle and his son Charles Huddle who were mining engineers in Ivanhoe, Virginia, and served in various capacities with the National Carbide Company; Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Corporation (formerly the Ivanhoe Furnace Company); New River Mineral Company; and Sand Mountain Sand Corporation. In addition, the collection contains some personal correspondence, memorabilia, and business papers of the family. Materials date from the 1850s to the 1970s.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was acquired by Special Collections in 1989.
Biographical Note
Charles Ross Huddle and his son Charles Richard Huddle were mining engineers in Ivanhoe, Virginia who served in various capacities with the National Carbide Company; Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Corporation (formerly the Ivanhoe Furnace Company); New River Mineral Company; and Sand Mountain Sand Corporation.
Scope and Content
This collection contains papers associated with Charles Ross Huddle and his son Charles Richard Huddle who were mining engineers in Ivanhoe, Virginia, and served in various capacities with the National Carbide Company; Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Corporation (formerly the Ivanhoe Furnace Company); New River Mineral Company; and Sand Mountain Sand Corporation. The papers include the Huddles' personal and business correspondence, W. F. Rupp's correspondence (business manager of the Ivanhoe Furnace Company's home office in Pittsburgh), and A. B. Dally's correspondence (chief executive officer of Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Corporation), reports, business ledgers, employee records, deeds, blueprints, and approximately 300 photographs of Ivanhoe and the businesses with which the Huddles were associated. The collection also includes Charles Richard Huddle's files on St. John's Episcopal Church and Wythe county, and the local Ruritan Club. Papers date from the 1850s to the 1970s.
Arrangement
The collection is in its original order. In addition to a folder-level list, the contents list below includes a brief description of the type of materials found in each box and the family member to which they relate.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Wythe County (Va.); Coal mines and mining; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South
Genre and Form Terms:
Ledgers (account books); Photographs
Persons:
Huddle, Charles, Sr.; Huddle, Royall; Huddle, Charles, Jr.
Corporate Names:
Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Corporation; Air Reduction Company; National Carbide Company
Contents List
- Box 1: Charles Huddle, Sr. Personal and Professional Papers; Huddle Family Land Documents
  - Charles Huddle Sr. Notebooks, 1910-1927 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. International Correspondence School Papers, 1913-1921 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. Correspondence and Employment at American Spar Company, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. memberships, 1920s (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Instructions and Blank Forms, 1920s (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. Geological Survey Correspondence, 1940-1953 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. Bills and Correspondence with Wysor Electric Appliance Co., Pulaski, Virginia, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. Personal Papers, 1943-1955 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Personal papers, 1946, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Esso Fuel Oil Bills, Charles Huddle Sr., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Charles Huddle Sr., Personal Letters and News Clippings (Box-folder 1-11)
  - Miscellaneous Papers connected to Charles Huddle Sr. (Box-folder 1-12)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. 1932-1933/ Ida Huddle 1973 (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. Miscellaneous Papers, 1888-1960 (Box-folder 1-14)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. Ration Books, Lodge Membership, Blank Stationary, Miscellaneous Papers (Box-folder 1-15)
  - Letters to and from Charles Huddle Sr., Mostly Personal (some replies) (Box-folder 1-16)
  - Huddle Family Correspondence, 1899-1931 (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Charles Huddle Sr. Geology and Ore Publications, 1906-1942 (Box-folder 1-18)
  - Deeds, Primarily Wythe County, Virginia, 1901-1913 (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Deeds, All Wythe County, Virginia, 1885-1900 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - Deeds and Contracts, Primarily Wythe County, Virginia, 1854-1906 (Box-folder 1-21)
  - Miscellaneous Huddle Business and Family Papers, 1886-1914 (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Paper on Isolation of Divalent Carbon by James P. Webb (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Machinery Advertisement Booklets, Morse Brothers Machinery Company (Box-folder 1-24)
- Box 2: National Carbide Company & Air Reduction Company Papers; Professional Papers
  - Louisville Air Pollution Newspaper Clippings, 1967 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - Carbide/Air Reduction Newspaper Clippings, 1960s (Box-folder 2-2)
  - National Carbide Company Newspaper Clippings, 1966-1979 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Receipts From Dalton Coal Yard, Signed by Charles Huddle Jr. and Richard Huddle, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Newspaper Clippings About New Jersey Zinc Plant Closing, 1981 (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings About Mineral Mining in Virginia, ca. 1962 (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Papers Concerning the Closing of Ivanhoe, Airco-Carbide Plant, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Papers Concerning National Carbide's Accounting Methods, 1953-1963 (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Excerpt From Article in the "Personnel Journal," September 1953 by Edward N. Hay (Box-folder 2-9)
  - Papers Concerning Investigation of Minerals in North Carolina and South Carolina, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 2-10)
  - Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle and Iss Van Horn, 1953 (Box-folder 2-11)
  - National Carbide Company and Air Reduction Chemical Carbide Company, Organizational Charts, Reassignment Bulletins, Operations Manual, Equal Employment Information, 1953-1967 (Box-folder 2-12)
  - Air Reduction Company Annual Report, 1962 (Box-folder 2-13)
  - Photos of Retiring Workers and a Safety Award, ca. 1960 (Box-folder 2-14)
  - Air Reduction Chemical and Carbide Company Press Releases, 1952-1964 (Box-folder 2-15)
  - National Carbide Manpower Reports and Frequency and Security Reports, 1962 (Box-folder 2-16)
  - Carbide and Airco Memos and Bulletins, 1949-1970 (Box-folder 2-17)
  - National Carbide Audit Memos, 1952-1966 (Box-folder 2-18)
  - Carbide Curve Reference File, 1945 (Box-folder 2-19)
  - Safety and Accident Reports from National Carbide Corporation, 1946-1963 (Box-folder 2-20)
  - National Carbide and Air Reduction Memos, Bulletins, Technical Data, 1948-1966 (Box-folder 2-21)
  - Acetylene File, Brochures, Regulations, Correspondence, 1930, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 2-22)
  - National Carbide Photos and Roster, 1956-1957, 1966 (Box-folder 2-23)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings About National Carbide Corporation Employees (Box-folder 2-24)
  - Skills and Proficiency and Management Company Papers, 1953 (Box-folder 2-25)
  - Germond and Air Reduction Co. Deed, 1955 (Box-folder 2-26)
  - Miscellaneous National Carbide Papers, 1953-1966 (Box-folder 2-27)
  - Miscellaneous National Carbide Papers, 1949-1960 (Box-folder 2-28)
  - Airco Insurance Conversion Problems, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 2-29)
  - Airco Expense Account Reports for Works Manager at Ivanhoe, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 2-30)
  - Lab Equipment Sale, 1966 (Box-folder 2-31)
  - Continental Oil Truck Information for New York, Charles Huddle Jr., 1968 (Box-folder 2-32)
  - Union Contract Booklets, 1950-1965 (Box-folder 2-33)
  - Office Machine Specs and Miscellaneous Correspondence, c.1960-1967 (Box-folder 2-34)
  - Charles Huddle Jr., Executive Documents, Business Correspondence, Employee Evaluations, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 2-35)
  - Land Negotiations, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 2-36)
  - Inventions/Patents Policy, 1950 (Box-folder 2-37)
- Box 3: Charles Huddle, Sr. Papers; National Carbide Company Papers
  - National Carbide Labor Turnover Quarterly Reports, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Airco, Inc. Medical Expense and Retirement Benefit Info, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Airco Retirement Income Plan, Booklets and Correspondence, 1951-1967 (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Airco Retirement Income Plan, Employee, Birthdate Information, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 3-4)
  - Employee Newsletters, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Employee Newsletter, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 3-6)
  - Employee Benefit Program Brochures, 1960-1977 (Box-folder 3-7)
  - Employee Seniority Lists, 1952-1966 (Box-folder 3-8)
  - Supervisor Responsibility Lists and Survey, 1952 (Box-folder 3-9)
  - Distribution of Salary Payroll, Reports and Correspondence, Ivanhoe Carbide, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 3-10)
  - Arbitration Cases Between National Carbide Co. and International Chemical Workers Union, 1949-1957 (Box-folder 3-11)
  - Employee Relations-Correspondence About Ivanhoe Employees With Mary Niven of Airco, Inc., 1960-1981 (Box-folder 3-12)
  - Accident Statistics, (personal information), 1964-1966 (Box-folder 3-13)
  - Charles Huddle Jr., Medical Claims/Bills, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 3-14)
  - Life Extension Institute Insurance Medical Exam for Charles Huddle Jr. (Box-folder 3-15)
  - Health Insurance Claims/Bills, 1944-1973 (Box-folder 3-16)
  - Employee Record: Akers, Frank M. (Box-folder 3-17)
  - Employee Record: Goodson, Thomas (Box-folder 3-18)
  - Employee Record: Groseclose, Elwood B. (Box-folder 3-19)
  - Employee Record: Hall, Walter A. (Box-folder 3-20)
  - Employee Record: Huddle, Charles R. (Jr.) (Box-folder 3-21)
  - Employee Record: Hudson, R. Stanford (Box-folder 3-22)
  - Employee Record: Hurst, William B. (Box-folder 3-23)
  - Employee Record: Jefferson, Conley O. (Box-folder 3-24)
  - Employee Record: Jefferson, Samuel W. (Box-folder 3-25)
  - Employee Record: Jones, Garland R. (Box-folder 3-26)
  - Employee Record: Jones, Howard F. (Box-folder 3-27)
  - Employee Record: King, Eli D. (Jr.) (Box-folder 2-28)
  - Employee Record: King, James J. (Box-folder 3-29)
  - Employee Record: Lawson, Gladis E. (Box-folder 3-30)
  - Employee Record: Leonard, Everett M. (Box-folder 3-31)
  - Employee Record: Payne, James P. (Box-folder 3-32)
  - Employee Record: Pickett, Eldrige C. (Box-folder 3-33)
  - Employee Record: Pickett, William R. (Box-folder 3-34)
  - Employee Record: Porter, Glen C. (Box-folder 3-35)
  - Employee Record: Rash, Timble E. (Box-folder 3-36)
  - Employee Record: Schreiber, George F. (Box-folder 3-37)
  - Employee Record: Sexton, Robert D. (Box-folder 3-38)
  - Employee Record: Spraker, Dallas E. (Box-folder 3-39)
  - Employee Record: Stoots, Jessee (Box-folder 3-40)
  - Employee Record: Underwood, Alvin M. (Box-folder 3-41)
  - Employee Record: Underwood, Everett C. (Box-folder 3-42)
  - Employee Record: Waller, Lester B (Box-folder 3-43)
  - Employee Record: Waller, Waldo E. (Box-folder 3-44)
  - Employee Record: Williams, John H. (Box-folder 3-45)
  - Employee Record: Wright, Sherman E. (Box-folder 3-46)
- Box 4: Business and Farm Papers and Ledgers
  - Charles Richard Huddle, Method Notes- Chemical Analysis Notebook, 1914 (Box-folder 4-1)
  - Ivanhoe Account Ledger, 1920-1922 and Ivanhoe Bills, 1921 (Box-folder 4-2)
  - Ivanhoe, "Record of Houses, Dwellings, Plant Buildings,", 1927-1929 (Box-folder 4-3)
  - Journal- Local Invoices, Bills, Etc., 1936-1943 (Box-folder 4-4)
  - Journal- Local Invoices, Bills, Etc., Inclusions, Part 1, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 4-5)
  - Journal- Local Invoices, Bills, Etc.- Inclusions Part II, 1915-1920 (Box-folder 4-6)
  - Journal- Local Invoices, Bills, Etc.- Inclusions Part III, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 4-7)
  - Sand Mountain Account Ledger, 1937-1942 (Box-folder 4-8)
  - Business Account Ledger, 1937-1944 (Box-folder 4-9)
  - Rent Ledger, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 4-10)
  - Rent Ledger Inclusions, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 4-11)
  - Business Account Ledger, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 4-12)
  - Farm Accounts, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 4-13)
  - Seniority Lists, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 4-14)
  - Survey Computation, 1926-1954 (Box-folder 4-15)
  - Farm Account Ledger and Loose Bills/Receipts, 1937-1944 (Box-folder 4-16)
  - Accident Prevention Certificate, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 4-17)
  - Worker Directory for Ivanhoe (Box-folder 4-1)
- Box 5: Photographs
  - Glass Negative: Man on a Horse (Box-folder 5-1)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs from Ivanhoe and Huddle Family Photographs (Box-folder 5-2)
  - Photographs from Ivanhoe Mining Co. including images of a flood in August of 1940 and a letter from Hartley Mays to C. R. Huddle Jr., 1940-1966 (Box-folder 5-3)
  - Photographs of Ivanhoe, ca. 1950s (Box-folder 5-4)
  - Mounted Photographs of Ivanhoe, c. 1900 (Box-folder 5-5)
  - Photographs from Ivanhoe, ca. 1894-1920 (Box-folder 5-6)
  - Photographs from Ivanhoe, ca. 1900-1966 (Box-folder 5-7)
  - Envelopes of Negatives from Ivanhoe (Box-folder 5-8)
  - Negatives from Ivanhoe (Box-folder 5-9)
  - Envelopes of Negatives from Ivanhoe (Box-folder 5-10)
  - Glass Negative and Print of Ivanhoe (Box-folder 5-11)
  - Glass Negative and Print of a Field from Ivanhoe (Box-folder 5-12)
- Box 6: Charles Huddle, Sr. Professional Correspondence and Business Papers
  - Cranberry Mine: Expenses for Burial of R. D. Burger, 1892 (Box-folder 6-1)
  - Record of Cost of Iron and Ore, Ivanhoe, Pilot Knob, Delton, and Gregory, 1899-1901 (Box-folder 6-2)
  - Cranberry Iron and Coal in Account with J. F. and G. Huddle, 1899 (Box-folder 6-3)
  - Ledgers- Ore Analysis, 1907-1915 (Box-folder 6-4)
  - Property Report and Two Leases for Ivanhoe, 1907, 1955 (Box-folder 6-5)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business Correspondence and Legal Papers, 1908-1928 (Box-folder 6-6)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. and Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Co. Furnace Repair Cost, c. 1915-1927 (Box-folder 6-7)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business and Personal Correspondence, 1910-1926 (Box-folder 6-8)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Co. Contracts, 1925-1931 (Box-folder 6-9)
  - Westinghouse, Church, and Kerr Company Materials, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 6-10)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. American Institute of Mining Engineers Membership, 1916-1919, 1960 (Box-folder 6-11)
  - Ivanhoe Furnace Corp. Business Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle Sr. and W. Eichleay, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 6-12)
  - Ivanhoe Furnace Corp. Charles R. Huddle Sr. Correspondence with the Carters, 1919-1922 (Box-folder 6-13)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Accounts, Receipts with Palo Co., 1919-1922 (Box-folder 6-14)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Correspondence with P.W. Fager, 1919-1924 (Box-folder 6-15)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Empty Envelopes, 1919-1926 (Box-folder 6-16)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Personal and Business Bills and Receipts, 1916-1929 (Box-folder 6-17)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting, Charles R. Huddle Sr. Hardware Store Bills, 1919-1930 (Box-folder 6-18)
  - Ivanhoe Furnace/Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Mechanical Drawings and Sketches, c.1920 (Box-folder 6-19)
  - Ivanhoe Furnace/Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting/Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business Correspondence, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 6-20)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence, 1919-1922 (Box-folder 6-21)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence Between A.B. Dally, G.W. Roden, and Charles R. Huddle Sr., 1917-1951 (Box-folder 6-22)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business Correspondence with W. K. Early and Son, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 6-23)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle Sr. and A. J. Miller, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 6-24)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle, Rupp, and Dally, April through December 1922 (Box-folder 6-25)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle Sr., Rupp, and Dally, 1933 (Box-folder 6-26)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence Charles R. Huddle Sr., 1924-1925 (Box-folder 6-27)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle Sr., Rupp, and Dally, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 6-28)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence Charles R. Huddle Sr. and Dally, 1927 (Box-folder 6-29)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business Correspondence with S. L. Boggs, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 6-30)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business Correspondence, 1931-1939
  - Examination of Prospects- Analysis of Ores, Metals, Etc., 1932-1937 (Box-folder 6-32)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Wytheville National Bank Cancelled Checks, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 6-33)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 6-34)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Business Correspondence Between Dally and Charles R. Huddle Sr. Concerning the Payroll, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 6-35)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 6-36)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Documents from Tennessee, Correspondence, Forms, Pay Checks, and Miscellaneous Papers, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 6-37)
  - Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle Sr. and A.B. Dally, 1943 (Box-folder 6-38)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Correspondence and Contacts, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 6-39)
  - Charles R. Huddle Sr. Business Correspondence, 1950-1966 (Box-folder 6-40)
- Box 7: Field Books; Charles Huddle, Sr. Professional Papers
  - Field Book detailing work done in Davidson County, North Carolina (Box-folder 7-1)
  - Field Book of Charles R. Huddle, Ivanhoe, Virginia (Box-folder 7-2)
  - Field Notebook of Charles R. Huddle (Details work at Green Mountain, NC) (Box-folder 7-3)
  - Field Book Belonging to Charles R. Huddle (Box-folder 7-4)
  - Field Book (Box-folder 7-5)
  - Miniature Ship Models Brochure and Ordering Materials Addressed to Charles R. Huddle (Box-folder 7-6)
  - Newspaper With Article Discussing Ivanhoe Union (Box-folder 7-7)
  - Cripple Creek Extension Map (Box-folder 7-8)
  - National Carbide Papers Regarding Extension of Telephone Line (Box-folder 7-9)
  - Era Papers Related to National Carbide, 1950s - 1960s (Box-folder 7-10)
  - Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Documents, Deeds, Blueprints of Land Tracts, Plans for a Boiler, c.1940s (Box-folder 7-11)
- Box 8: Charles Huddle, Sr. Professional and Personal Papers; Memorabilia; Newsclippings
  - Wythe County, Virginia Community Information Packet, ca. 1970 (Box-folder 8-1)
  - Wythe County Historical Society Materials, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 8-2)
  - Miscellaneous News Clippings related to Mary Huddle, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 8-3)
  - Tanglewood Farm Account Book, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 8-4)
  - San Francisco Tourist Information, ca. 1950 (Box-folder 8-5)
  - Carcassi's Complete Method for the Guitar (Box-folder 8-6)
  - Postage Stamp Collection (Box-folder 8-7)
  - Charles Richard Huddle Jr., Stoeger Arms Corporation Orders, 1945 (Box-folder 8-8)
  - Charles R. Huddle Jr. Episcopal Church Mementos, 1934-1973 (Box-folder 8-9)
  - Boericke and Tafel Homeopathic Pharmacists and Publishers Materials, 1954 (Box-folder 8-10)
  - Charles R. Huddle Jr. Ruritan Club of Ivanhoe, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 8-11)
  - Charles R. Huddle Jr.St. Johns Episcopal Church in Wytheville, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 8-12)
  - Charles R. Huddle Jr. St Johns Episcopal Church in Wytheville, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 8-13)
  - Appalachian Power Company Electric Bills for Charles R. Huddle Jr. and Mrs. J.C. Lawson, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 8-14)
  - Charles R. Huddle Jr. Miscellaneous Papers, 1960-1981 (Box-folder 8-16)
  - Letter from Charles R. Huddle Jr. to His Mother and Father, 1947 (Box-folder 8-16)
  - Miscellaneous News Clippings, ca. 1960s and 1970s (Box-folder 8-17)
  - Letters from Charles R. Huddle Sr. and Ida Huddle to Their Son Charles R. Huddle Jr., 1945-1947 (Box-folder 8-18)
  - Documents Concerning Sand Mountain Sand Co., 1937-1945 (Box-folder 8-19)
  - Charles R. Huddle (Probably Sr.) Correspondence and Miscellaneous Papers Concerning Sand Mountain Sand Corp. and Ivanhoe Mining and Smelting Co., 1932-1946 (Box-folder 8-20)
  - Deeds and Agreements for Sand Mountain Sand Corp., 1937-1951 (Box-folder 8-21)
  - Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle and Business Records for Sand Mountain Sand (Box-folder 8-22)
  - Finances, Deeds, Business Correspondence for Sand Mountain Sand Corp., 1941-1943 (Box-folder 8-23)
  - Finances and Business Correspondence With Sand Mountain Sand Corp., 1943 (Box-folder 8-24)
  - Correspondence With Wythe County National Bank and Sand Mountain Sand Corp., 1943-1944 (Box-folder 8-25)
  - Business Correspondence Between Charles R. Huddle Jr. and Sand Mountain Sand Corp., 1940-1951 (Box-folder 8-26)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute Virginia Water Resources Research Booklet, Development and Management of Water Facilities for Small Communities, Proceedings of a Conference, September 24-25, 1981 (Box-folder 8-27)
  - Reports on Examination of Financial Statements Wythe-Bland Water and Sewer Authority Wytheville, Virginia, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 8-28)
  - Contract for Siloam Branch Ivanhoe Water Extension Wythe-Bland Water and Sewer Authority, 1979 (Box-folder 8-29)
  - Wythe-Bland Water Authority- News Clippings, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 8-30)
  - Materials Relating to Siloam Branch Ivanhoe Water Extension, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 8-31)
  - Folder for Insurance Records of Ida L. Huddle, unspecified date-1983 (Box-folder 8-32)
- Box 9: Charles Huddle, Sr., Charles Huddle, Jr., and Royall Huddle Correspondence
  - Correspondence Between and Charles Sr. and Royall Huddle, 1915-1920 (Box-folder 9-1)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Sr. and Royall Huddle, 1921-1926 (Box-folder 9-2)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Sr. and Royall Huddle, Postcards, and Some Photographs, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 9-3)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Sr. and Royall Huddle, 1930-1935 (Box-folder 9-4)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Sr. and Royall Huddle, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 9-5)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Sr. and Royall Huddle, 1950-1957 (Box-folder 9-6)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Sr. and Royall Huddle, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 9-7)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Sr. and Royall Huddle (Box-folder 9-8)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Jr. and Royall Huddle, 1922-1949 (Box-folder 9-9)
  - Correspondence Between Charles Jr. and Royall Huddle, 1950-1957 (Box-folder 9-10)
- Box 10: Charles Huddle, Sr. Professional Papers, Business Records/Documents
  - State Corporation Commission of Virginia- Copies of Annual Reports (Box-folder 10-1)
  - Corporation Commission of Virginia Reciepts for Registration and Tax Correspondence (Box-folder 10-2)
  - Reports on Analysis- Copies, Laboratory Correspondence (Box-folder 10-3)
  - Letter from Secretary at Ivanhoe to C.R. Huddle, Request for Information to Substantiate Ledger Account (Box-folder 10-4)
  - General Correspondence of A. B. Dally (Box-folder 10-5)
  - General Correspondence of A.L. Dally- 1957 and C.R. Huddle Stock Certificate (Box-folder 10-6)
  - Receipts for Farm Equipment Purchases C. R. Huddle (Box-folder 10-7)
  - C. R. Huddle Waynesboro Expenses Receipts, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 10-8)
  - C. R. Huddle Payment Vouchers and Correspondence (Box-folder 10-9)
  - Insurance Documents (Box-folder 10-10)
  - Worker's Compensation Insurance Papers C. R. Huddle (Box-folder 10-11)
  - Papers Concerning Midvale Mine in Rockbridge County, Virginia, 1954 (Box-folder 10-12)
  - Correspondence Between C. R. Huddle and Law Firm of Parson's and Arthur (Box-folder 10-13)
  - C.R. Huddle Misc. Correspondence (Box-folder 10-14)
  - Mining Methods Data (Box-folder 10-15)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence of C.R. Huddle and Mining Reports (Box-folder 10-16)
  - Mining Reports and Records (Box-folder 10-17)